instinctmagazine.com 2018-12-26

# Privacy Policy | Instinct

**What information do we collect?**  
We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to our newsletter, respond to a survey or fill out a form.

When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your: name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number or credit card information. You may, however, visit our site anonymously.

**What do we use your information for?**  
Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To personalize your experience  
(your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)
  * To improve our website  
(we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)
  * To improve customer service  
(your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)
  * To process transactions
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
  * To send periodic emails
  * Physical mailing information may be periodically shared with specific third-parties who agree to keep your information confidential.

The email address you provide may be used to send you information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions.

Note: If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.

**How do we protect your information?**  
We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order.

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential.

After a transaction, your private information (credit cards, social security numbers, financials, etc.) will not be stored on our servers.

**Do we use cookies?**  
Yes (Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computers hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites or service providers systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information.

We use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart, understand and save your preferences for future visits, keep track of advertisements and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.

Some of our advertisers may also use cookies to collect information on our site visitors.

If you prefer, you can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is being sent, or you can choose to turn off all cookies via your browser settings. Like most websites, if you turn your cookies off, some of our services may not function properly. However, you can still place orders over the telephone or by contacting customer service.

**How do we analyze our users?**

We use the Google Analytics service to learn more about our users ("Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting").  This includes demographic information such as age, gender, and interests.

Using Google's [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads), you can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads.

**Do we disclose any information to outside parties?**

With the exception of physical mailing information, we do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

**Third party links**  
Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites.

**California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**  
Because we value your privacy we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act. We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

As part of the California Online Privacy Protection Act, all users of our site may make any changes to their information at anytime by logging into their account and visiting <https://instinctmagazine.com/user/me/edit>.

**Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance**  
We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Childrens Online Privacy Protection Act), we do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

**Online Privacy Policy Only**  
This online privacy policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.

**Your Consent**  
By using our site, you consent to our [privacy policy](http://www.freeprivacypolicy.com/).

**Changes to our Privacy Policy**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.
